A Finding Aid to the Lucy R. Lippard Papers, 1930s-2007, bulk 1960s-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.lipplucy
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, 1950s-circa 1990s; Series 8; 1 Linear feet Boxes 50, 53, OV 71
  Series consists primarily of photographic prints, with some negatives and slides. Photographs of exhibition installations of various artists and galleries include Tal Streeter at Ame Gallery in 1965, Walter De Maria at Paula Johnson Gallery in 1965, and Andy Warhol exhibitions at Leo Castelli, Stable Gallery and Ferus Gallery.
  One folder of photographs of artists includes photos of Marcel Duchamp, Lyman Kipp (by Hans Namuth), J. J. Lebel, Sheldon Machlin and Robert Murray. Also found is a photograph of a street scene with a man identified as Red Grooms standing on a rooftop. This photo was possibly enclosed with correspondence to Lippard but the correspondent is not identified on the photograph.
  A folder of movie stills includes photographic prints of Hollywood actors and actresses from films such as Jane Eyre, National Velvet, and Wuthering Heights. Actors featured include Fred Astaire and Ginger Rogers, Joan Fontaine, Sophia Loren, Laurence Olivier, Elizabeth Taylor and Spencer Tracy with Katherine Hepburn among others. The photographs were pasted on what appear to be scrapbook pages.
  Additional photographic material can be found throughout the collection, particularly in Series 2.
  - Exhibition Artwork (Box 50)
    - "Dada, Surrealism and their Heritage" (1968), circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - "Great Ideas of Western Man" (1971), circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - "The Passionate Years: Expressionism in Germany" (date unknown), circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - "Woman" (date unknown), circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (1980), 1980-1981 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Installations (Box 50)
    - Installations (1959-1989), 1960s-1989 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Installations, Various (undated), circa 1950s-circa 1990s (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Installatious, Unidentified, circa 1950s-circa 1990s (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - People, Artists, circa 1960s (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - People, Movie Prints, circa 1930s-circa 1960s (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - People, Unidentified, circa 1960s-circa 1990s (Box 50, Folder 15-16)
  - Works of Art (Box 50)
    Arranged alphabetically by surname of artist and then chronologically within each artist.
    - By Artists, A, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - By Artists, B, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 18-19)
    - By Artists, C, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - By Artists, D, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 21-22)
    - By Artists, E-F, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - By Artists, G, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - By Artists, H, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - By Artists, I, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - By Artists, J, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - By Artists, K, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 28)
    - By Artists, L, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - By Artists, M, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - By Artists, N, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - By Artists, O, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - By Artists, P, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - By Artists, R, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 34)
    - By Artists, S, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 35-36)
    - By Artists, T, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - By Artists, V, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 38)
    - By Artists, W, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 39)
    - By Artists, Z, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - By Artists, Pre 20th Century, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - By Artists, Early 20th Century, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 42-43)
    - By Artists, Unidentified, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 44-45)
    - By Artists, Unidentified or Illegible, circa 1950s-circa 1990s (Box 50, Folder 46)
    - By Artists, Unidentified-Negatives, circa 1960s (Box 50, Folder 47)
    - By Artists, Unidentified-Transparencies, circa 1960s-circa 1970s (Box 50, Folder 48)
  - Oversized By Artists, D housed with Box 50, Folders 21-22 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Exhibition Installations housed with Box 50, Folder 9 (Box OV 71)